XIAOYU A. GAO

6812 Dean Drive, McLean VA, 22101 | (703) 901-0568 | aki@alluminate.io | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack Javascript Developer with a passion for technology and innovation. My experience and expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures and devops pipelines using Agile development methodologies. In particular, I specialize in technologies such as React/Redux, Node.js/Express, Webpack, Docker, Terraform, Jenkins and AWS.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

- Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering
- Rodman Scholar (Honors Program for Top 5% of Engineers)

Skills

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7/ES8), Shell (Bash), Java, C/C++

UX/UI and Front End Web Technologies and Tools:

• Sketch, HTML5, CSS3/CSS4, React, Redux, CSS Modules, PostCSS

Devops Technologies:

• Travis, CircleCI, Jenkins, Terraform, Packer

Development and Testing Tools:

 Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Git, Mocha, Chai, Webpack, Babel, NPM, Yarn

Back End Web and Database Technologies:

Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB

Infrastructure Technologies and Cloud Services:

• Docker, AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean

Work Experience

Alluminate - Fullstack Developer/Technology Consultant

October 2017 - Present

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities to in-house and consulting working ranging from UX/UI to cloud architecture.
- CoinScore October 2017 Present
 - CoinScore is a Digital Asset Intelligence Platform that provides technical and sentiment analysis for cryptocurrencies and tokens.
 - Designed the landing page in Sketch.
- CryptoPets November 2017 Present
 - CryptoPets is a Blockchain-based game platform for collecting, breeding, and battling digital pets.
 - Designed and implemented the first iterations of the landing page in WebFlow.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application July 2017 August 2017
 - Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure.
 - Front end built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form and styled with Spectre.css and custom CSS as a static SPA.
 - Back end written in Node.js, and data is persisted on Azure CosmoDB as a MongoDB Database, as well as on the Microsoft's private Ethereum Blockchain.
 - Smart contracts written in Solidity with Truffle and deployed to Microsoft's Blockchain network.
 - Infrastructure provisioned with Terraform, and front end and back end build and deployment automated with Jenkins.
 - SPA and API deployed on Azure Blob Storage and Web Apps respectively, and Geth nodes hosted on Microsoft's Blockchain as a Service.
 - Front end files stored in Blob storage proxied with Azure Function App Service to allow accessing static files as website URL.
 - Architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project.
 - Led development efforts across the stack, including the UX/UI design, front end, back end and devops, in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
 - Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
- FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment September 2017 November 2017
 - Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment Project.
 - Front end logic built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form, and user interface styled with custom CSS4 using CSS modules and PostCSS.
 - Application transpiled using Babel with a custom written Webpack configuration.
 - Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI, implementing application logic, and providing high level guidance to other developers.